The rise and fall of the Corleone empire.
The Godfather Part II is a drama, crime film directed by Francis Ford Coppola.
In the continuing saga of the Corleone crime family, a young Vito
Corleone grows up in Sicily and in 1910s New York.
In the 1950s, Michael Corleone attempts to expand the family
business into Las Vegas, Hollywood and Cuba.
Don Michael Corleone, played by Al Pacino.
Tom Hagen, played by Robert Duvall.
Kay Corleone, played by Diane Keaton.
Vito Corleone, played by Robert De Niro.
Frederico 'Fredo' Corleone, played by John Cazale.
Constanzia 'Connie' Corleone, played by Talia Shire.
The Godfather Part II is a 1974 American epic gangster film produced and directed by Francis Ford Coppola,
loosely based on the 1969 novel The Godfather by Mario Puzo, who co-wrote the screenplay with Coppola.
It is both a sequel and a prequel to the 1972 film The Godfather, presenting parallel dramas: one picks up the 1958 story of Michael Corleone (Al Pacino), the new Don of the Corleone family, protecting the family business
in the aftermath of an attempt on his life; the other covers the journey of his father, Vito Corleone (Robert De Niro), from his Sicilian childhood to the founding of his family enterprise in New York City.
The ensemble cast also features Robert Duvall, Diane Keaton, Talia Shire,
Morgana King, John Cazale, Marianna Hill and Lee Strasberg.
Following the first film's success, Paramount Pictures began developing
a follow-up, with many of the cast and crew returning.
Coppola, who was given more creative control, had wanted to make both a sequel and a prequel
to The Godfather that would tell the story of Vito's rise and Michael's fall.
Principal photography began in October 1973 and wrapped up in June 1974.
The Godfather Part II premiered in New York City on December 12, 1974, and
was released in the United States on December 20, 1974.
It grossed $48 million in the United States and Canada and up to
$93 million worldwide on a $13 million budget.
The film was nominated for eleven Academy Awards and
became the first sequel to win Best Picture.
Its six Oscar wins also included Best Director for Coppola, Best Supporting Actor
for De Niro, and Best Adapted Screenplay for Coppola and Puzo.
Pacino won Best Actor at the BAFTAs and was nominated at the Oscars.
The Godfather Part II is considered to be one of the greatest films of all time,
as well as a rare example of a sequel that rivals its predecessor.
Like its predecessor, Part II remains a highly influential
film, especially in the gangster genre.
In 1997, the American Film Institute ranked it as the 32nd-greatest film in
American film history and it retained this position 10 years later.
It was selected for preservation in the US National Film Registry of the Library of Congress in
1993, being deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
Pauline Kael wrote: "The Godfather was the greatest gangster picture ever made, and
had metaphorical overtones that took it far beyond the gangster genre.
In Part II, the wider themes are no longer merely implied.
The second film shows the consequences of the actions in the first; it’s all one movie, in two great big pieces, and it comes together in
your head while you watch."
The Godfather Part III, the final installment in the trilogy, was released 16 years later in 1990.
The film explores themes of new year's eve, new york city,
based on novel or book, italian american, cuba.
The tone is emotional.